Interviewer: To be born a realized soul is a gift from God.
Shri Mataji: Of course. Of course. Apart from that these days are many children who are children of the Sahaja Yogis are born realized.
Shri Mataji: Yes, it's very surprising that I think all the great souls want to take birth with the Sahaja Yogis.
Interviewer: What is your opinion about hatha yoga?
Shri Mataji:  hatha yoga is a thing which was preached by or written by Patanjali thousands of years back.
Shri Mataji:  And in those days, first they used to cleanse the person. It is Ashtanga, eight. There are eight Anga, means parts.
Shri Mataji:  And one of the parts is the wee bit of that is this exercise, the physical exercise.
Shri Mataji:  So his style was to cleanse a person first physically, then mentally, then emotionally, go on and on and on. And then he would get realization.
Shri Mataji: One in a million would get realization. That was the tradition.
Shri Mataji: So I have thought of the modern times. People have no time for anything.
Shri Mataji: So Sahaja Yoga is a very quick method.
Shri Mataji: First get your realization and then you correct yourself.
Shri Mataji:  And no obligation. You yourself know about yourself.
Shri Mataji:  For example, some Sahaja Yogi might come and say, Mother, I have a very bad Agnya. It means I have a very bad ego. But normally nobody says like that.
Shri Mataji:  That I am full of ego. But nobody says because suddenly introspection starts.
Shri Mataji: And you want to correct yourself. And you know how to correct.
Interviewer: So how do we come to the balance between the love for ourselves and love for others?
Shri Mataji:  You become love, that's all.
Shri Mataji:  I mean your self is lost like a drop in the ocean notion. Your self is lost in the ocean of love, say. So all limitations drop off. You become love.
Interviewer: She says it looks simple but it is very difficult. When somebody hurts you, then one tends to react.
Shri Mataji: You see, if somebody hurts you, it is you forgive in the easiest way.
Shri Mataji: But if you are going to feel it, then he is stronger than you.
Shri Mataji: Just forgive. That you will learn in Sahaja Yoga very easily.
Shri Mataji: It's fun.
Yogi: She wants to put a question to me personally.
Yogi: I must say that I had a very strong experience. I was at a public conference of Shri Mataji 18 years ago in Rome.
Yogi: As soon as Shri Mataji entered the room, there was a kind of recognition. It seemed to me that I had always known her.
Yogi: Then Shri Mataji gave me this experience of awakening. I immediately felt these vibrations.
Yogi: But more than anything else, I felt inside, apart from this peace, this serenity, a sense of lightness.
Yogi: It seemed to me that it lasted even for several days. It seemed to me to walk down the street, to be lifted from the ground.
Yogi: People who knew me also told me that I had a new light on my face. It was an incredible feeling.
Hành giả: Cảm giác đó giống như đang yêu.
Hành giả: Cảm giác đó còn tuyệt hơn.
Người phỏng vấn: Hành trình của bạn tiếp diễn như thế nào?
Hành giả: Cứ cho là vài ngày sau, bạn bắt đầu nghĩ về bản ngã của mình.
Hành giả: Đó thực sự là cơn ác mộng tồi tệ nhất của chúng tôi. Bạn bắt đầu tự hỏi mình đang làm gì.
Hành giả: Tôi về nhà, tôi đóng hết cửa sổ để xem làn gió mát đó có thật không hay chỉ là những luồng gió hoặc từ máy điều hòa.
Hành giả: Rồi bạn nhận ra rằng đây mới là thực tại.
Hành giả: Nếu bạn đặt tay lên một người và cảm nhận những rung động năng lượng của họ, nếu bạn cảm nhận được ngón tay này, điều đó có nghĩa là đó là gan của người đó.
Hành giả: Rồi bạn đến với điều lớn lao hơn.
Hành giả: Bạn cảm nhận được mối liên kết với các Hành giả Sahaja.
Hành giả: Tôi có thể nói rằng đó là thiên đường tại thế.
Hành giả: Nhưng không ai đến được đó, vì không ai có thể nhận ra điều đó nếu họ không tự mình trải nghiệm.
Hành giả: Tôi đang nói rằng các Hành giả Sahaja giống như thiên đường tại thế.
Shri Mataji: Có một thiên đường bên trong chúng ta, trong chính chúng ta. Chúng ta chỉ cần tìm kiếm nó. Đó là sự thật.
Hành giả: Cô ấy muốn có được trải nghiệm đó.
Shri Mataji: Được thôi.